Sarah Jacobs

Atlanta, Georgia

Email: sgjacobs14@gmail.com

Phone: 678-977-7919

Portfolio: sarahgjacobs.github.io/sjportfolio LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sarahgjacobs GitHub: github.com/sarahgjacobs

Driven Software Developer with two years of experience in web development. Strong background including digital media, communication, and leadership development. Highly motivated entrepreneur with a passion for creating lasting impressions.

Languages and Tools

JavaScript, React, CSS, HTML, SQL, MySQL, jQuery, GitHub, Git, Version Control, MongoDB, Express, Node, Bootstrap, SDLC, Agile Methodology, OOP, API

Projects

BlogIt github.com/sarahgjacobs/blogit

- BlogIt is an interactive, modern blogging website that allows users to register, login, browse and upload articles. It provides an intuitive and user-friendly interface for individuals to share their thoughts, ideas, and experiences with the world.
- Oversaw entire project development of front end and back end.
- Tools and languages used include Front End Development, Back End Development, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, APIs, Agile Methodology, DOM, Version Control, and GitHub.

PawPals github.com/thebobfather2/pawpals

- PawPals allows users to search for their next adoptable pet. The project uses handlebars to produce each page, MySQL to store the animal cards, and features a login functionality for users to apply for adoption.
- Managed delegation of roles, creation of mockups, qualifications of MVP, development of front end development, organization of MVC, and assistance of SQL database setup.
- Tools and languages used include Full Stack development, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Agile Methodology, DOM, Node, Express, Heroku, MySQL and GitHub.

Technical Work Experience

Coding Coach

The Coder School

July 2023 - Current Suwannee, GA

- Instructed classes for elementary kids in Scratch to encourage problem solving and logical thinking
- Oversaw development of coding classes in one on one weekly environments
- Created and supported learnings goals in students to encourage computer confidence

Digital Media Coordinator Comfort Farms/StagVets

Aug 2020 - May 2021 Milledgeville, GA

- Developed front end of Square, Wix and Donorbox utilizing HTML and CSS for fundraisers and sales
- Enhanced user experience through increased efficiency by organizing primary landing pages
- Pioneered integral solutions to drive traffic toward online shopping center and resources for retired Veterans
- Managed team of 4 for creation and deployment of all technological promotion including videos and photos
- Pioneered Donorbox development of 10+ support-raising programs upwards of \$50,000 each

Relevant Work Experience

Self Employed English Tutor Self Employed

May 2021 - Current Atlanta, GA

- Launched private tutoring business for expat families in Atlanta
- Improved testing scores and reading comprehension to become as proficient as 100%
- Formulated personal lesson plans for 20+ students ranging from elementary kids to middle aged adults
- Fostered long-term relationships with international Japanese and Korean families in America

Communication and Media Coordinator Second Level

May 2021 - Sept 2022 Atlanta, GA

- Lead technology team for annual community conference and quarterly digital projects
- Produced media for global website and print promotion of over 50 countries
- Coordinated company-wide digital media and brand unity to establish trust in the community
- Programmed monthly MailChimp e-newsletter for over 1,000 recipients
- Assisted weekly ESOL class and fostered one on one relationships with international families

Leadership Development Coach, Customer Service Representative Chick-Fil-A Restaurants

Aug 2015 - May 2021 Alpharetta, GA

- Established and oversaw generational leadership training program of an \$8M+ store
- Pioneered mentorship and training of 60+ employees
- Managed night time finances processing \$20k a day
- Facilitated refunds, coupons and promotions through Chick-Fil-A One app and POS system

Education

Coding Certificate: Georgia Tech

Atlanta, Georgia, 2023

• 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Java, jQuery, Progressive Web Apps, Agile Methodology, React, Express, Node, MongoDB, SQL, OOP, Command Line, Git, and Bootstrap

Georgia College & State University

Milledgeville, Georgia, 2021

• BA in Communication with a concentration in Digital Media